二零零八年，普通高等学校招生。全国统一考试听力部分，该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案。转涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
Hello, International Friends Club, can I help you?
Oh, hello, I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
试音到此结束，听力考试正式开始。请看听力部分。第一节，第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后。你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题，每段对话仅读一遍。例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的。价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并将其标在试卷上。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。答。
1. I think it's going to rain.
I guess so.
The skies are dark and cloudy.
Text 2. Lucy is going back to China next month, Alice.
Oh really? And she will not take Rachel this time.
Text 3. hate to say it, but Jackie isn't doing well in the film.
Well, I think he's only playing a different type of role.
My sister thinks he's still the best.
Text 4. Professor Miners, could I talk to you about my paper?
Sure. Come to my office between 2 to 3.
It's room 340.
Text 5. Okay, time to go home.
I can't. I haven't finished the report about the newly opened restaurant.
Well, if you carry on working like that, you'll make yourself ill.
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白。读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
That's great. How old is
I haven't seen you for a long time.
Where have you been?
stayed there for two months.
Actually, I really went to meet my new nephew.
That's great. How old is he?
Well, he was five months old when I got there, and he could possibly be the most
beautiful baby I've ever seen.
What did you do in your sister's home?
I held the baby and played with him a lot, which was nice.
But what I enjoyed most was feeding him.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Text 7. Air pollution is so bad in this city.
I think the government should stop people from driving cars on certain days.
You have a point.
Air pollution is a problem.
But not letting people drive on certain days is a bad idea.
People have to go to work by car.
I'm afraid I don't agree with you there.
Reducing air pollution is really important.
People are so used to driving that they don't think of other ways to do things.
If we stopped them from driving on certain days, maybe they could think of new ways
to get around.
I see your point.
But I still think it wouldn't be possible to stop people from driving.
Text 8. Air pollution is so bad in this city.
I think the government should stop people from driving cars on certain days.
You have a point.
Air pollution is a problem.
But not letting people drive on certain days is a bad idea.
People have to go to work by car.
I'm afraid I don't agree with you there.
Reducing air pollution is really important.
People are so used to driving that they don't think of other ways to do things.
If we stopped them from driving on certain days, maybe they could think of new ways
to get around.
I see your point.
But I still think it wouldn't be possible to stop people from driving.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至十三小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小。
Text 8. Let's go and have lunch together.
Okay. the way, I'm thinking of going to New Zealand around Christmas for three
weeks. It's such a beautiful country.
I've never been there before.
Have you booked the flight?
Not yet. I'm planning to book my flight in two weeks' time.
Book your flight right now.
Why? Because the longer you leave it, the more expensive it'll will be.
As a matter of fact, the prices may double at Christmas time.
New Zealanders usually go home for Christmas.
Then I'm going to book my flight tomorrow morning.
Let's go and have lunch together.
Okay. By the way, I'm thinking of going to New Zealand around Christmas for three
weeks. It's such a beautiful country.
I've never been there before.
Have you booked the flight?
Not yet. I'm planning to book my flight in two weeks' time.
Book your flight right now.
Why? Because the longer you leave it, the more expensive it'll will be.
As a matter of fact, the prices may double at Christmas time.
New Zealanders usually go home for Christmas.
Then I'm going to book my flight tomorrow morning.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至十七小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个。小题。
Text 9. Hello?
Hello, Mike. This is
Oh, hello, Jane.
Listen, Mike, I've got a real problem.
What is it?
The car's broken down.
Oh, not again.
Yeah, I checked the oil, and I checked almost everything.
It's just not starting at all.
You'll have to get rid of it, you know?
I know, I know.
But look, the thing is, I've got to Tom up at the airport.
Can I? Use my car?
Yes, of course.
That'll be great.
It's a very kind of you.
Come around when you like.
I don't need it till tonight.
Okay. I'll be around in about an hour.
Thanks a lot.
It's all right.
See you then.
See you. Hello?
Hello, Mike. This is Jane.
Oh, hello, Jane.
Listen, Mike, I've got a real problem.
What is it?
The car's broken down.
Oh, not again.
Yeah, I checked the oil, and I checked almost everything.
It's just not starting at all.
You'll have to get rid of it, you know?
I know, I know.
But look, the thing is, I've got to pick Tom up at the airport.
Can I? Use my car?
Yes, of course.
That'll be great.
It's a very kind of you.
Come around when you like.
I don't need it till tonight.
Okay. I'll be around in about an hour.
Thanks a lot.
It's all right.
See you then.
See you. Text 10.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至二十小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Okay, when we met last week, we talked about different kinds of short stories, and
some well -known short story writers.
I remember that many of you said you liked the American writer, Ernest Hemingway,
right? I hope you all followed my advice and finished reading his story, A Day's
Wait, because as I said, we're going to study it together in today's lesson.
Now, since you're supposed to have read the story, let's have some discussion.
Please look at the four questions on the blackboard.
First, when and where does the story take place?
Second, what does the boy wait for in the story, and what kind of person does he
show himself to be?
Third, what kind of person is the boy's father?
Fourth, what is the writer's main purpose of writing this story?
I'd like you to work in groups of or five and present your answers in 10 minutes.
Is everything clear?
Okay, when we met last week, we talked about different kinds of short stories, and
some well -known short story writers.
I remember that many of you said you liked the American writer, Ernest Hemingway,
right? I hope you all followed my advice and finished reading his story, A Day's
Wait, because as I said, we're going to study it together in today's lesson.
Now, since you're supposed to have read the story, let's have some discussion.
Please look at the four questions on the blackboard.
First, when and where does the story take place?
Second, what does the boy wait for in the story, and what kind of person does he
show himself to be?
Third, what kind of person is the boy's father?
Fourth, what is the writer's main purpose of writing this story?
I'd like you to work in groups of or five and present your answers in 10 minutes.
Is everything clear?
第二。二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听力部分到此结束。